<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.sonicdcer.Starfox64Recomp</id>
  <name>Starfox 64 Recompiled</name>
  <developer id="io.github.sonicdcer.Starfox64Recomp">
    <name>Starfox64Recomp Contributors</name>
    <url>https://github.com/sonicdcer/Starfox64Recomp/graphs/contributors/</url>
  </developer>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#9d6aa6</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#603e67</color>
  </branding>
  <summary>Recompiled port of Starfox 64</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.sonicdcer.Starfox64Recomp.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/sonicdcer/Starfox64Recomp</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/sonicdcer/Starfox64Recomp</url>
  <description>
    <p>Starship is a project that uses N64: Recompiled to statically recompile
      Starfox 64 into a native port with many new features, enhancements, and extensive mod
      support. This project uses RT64 as the rendering engine to provide some of these
      enhancements.</p>
    <ul>
      <li><em>Plug and Play</em> - Simply provide your copy of the 1.1 (Rev A) North American
        version of the game in the main menu and start playing! This project will automatically
        load assets from the provided copy, so there is no need to go through a separate
        extraction step or build the game yourself. Other versions of the game may be supported
        in the future.</li>
      <li><em>Fully Intact N64 Effects</em> - A lot of care was put into RT64 to make sure all
        graphical effects were rendered exactly as they did originally on the N64. No workarounds
        or "hacks" were made to replicate these effects, with the only modifications to them
        being made for enhancement purposes such as widescreen support.</li>
      <li><em>Easy-to-Use Menus</em> - Gameplay settings, graphics settings, input mappings,
        and audio settings can all be configured with the in-game config menu. The menus
        can all be used with mouse, controller, or keyboard for maximum convenience.</li>
      <li><em>High Framerate Support</em> - Play at any framerate you want thanks to
        functionality provided by RT64! Game objects and terrain, texture scrolling, screen
        effects, and most HUD elements are all rendered at high framerates. By default,
        this project is configured to run at your monitor's refresh rate. You can also
        play at the original framerate of the game if you prefer. Changing framerate has
        no effect on gameplay. <em>Note:</em> External framerate limiters (such as the NVIDIA
        Control Panel) are known to potentially cause problems, so if you notice any stuttering
        then turn them off and use the manual framerate slider in the in-game graphics menu
        instead.</li>
      <li><em>Widescreen and Ultrawide Support</em> - Any aspect ratio is supported, with
        most effects modded to work correctly in widescreen. The HUD can also be positioned
        at 16:9 when using ultrawide aspect ratios if preferred. <em>Note:</em> Some animation
        quirks can be seen at the edges of the screen in certain cutscenes when using very
        wide aspect ratios.</li>
      <li><em>Mod Support</em> - Install community made mods and texture packs! Mods can
        change any part of the game, including adding completely new features and content.
        You can install mods by simply dragging the mod files onto the game window before
        starting the game or by clicking the <em>Install Mods</em> button in the mod menu.
        Mods can be toggled in the mod menu, and some mods can be configured there as
        well.</li>
      <li><em>Additional Control Options</em> - Customize your experience by setting your
        stick deadzone to your liking, as well as adjusting the Y axis inversion for aiming.</li>
      <li><em>Low Input Lag</em> - This project has been optimized to have as little input
        lag as possible, making the game feel more responsive than ever!</li>
      <li><em>Instant Load Times</em> - Saving and loading files, going from place to
        place, and pausing all happen in the blink of an eye thanks to the game running
        natively on modern hardware.</li>
      <li><em>Linux and Steam Deck Support</em> - A Linux binary as well as a Flatpak is
        available for playing on most up-to-date distros, including on the Steam Deck.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Starship does not include any copyrighted assets. You are required to provide a
      supported copy of the game.</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image type="source">https://images.igdb.com/igdb/image/upload/t_720p/scsf8v.webp</image>
      <caption>Woodfall Temple</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image type="source">https://evilgames.eu/texture-packs/img/mm-n64hd-01.jpg</image>
      <caption>HD texture pack</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
    <category>ActionGame</category>
  </categories>
  <supports>
    <control>keyboard</control>
  </supports>
  <recommends>
    <control>gamepad</control>
  </recommends>
  <provides>
    <binary>Starship</binary>
  </provides>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>action</keyword>
    <keyword>shooter</keyword>
    <keyword>starfox</keyword>
    <keyword>decompile</keyword>
    <keyword>recompile</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.0.3" date="2025-12-30">
      <url>https://github.com/sonicdcer/Starfox64Recomp/releases/tag/1.0.3</url>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
